anedot.com 2017-06-20

# Anedot

Last Modified on May 5, 2016

## Our Privacy Commitment

Anedot, Inc. (“ ** _Anedot_** ,” “ ** _we_** ,” “ ** _us_** ” or “ ** _our_** ”) is committed to respecting the privacy rights and concerns of all users of Anedot’s website where this Privacy Policy is posted (the “ ** _Site_** ”) (we refer to the Site, the services and the software made available by Anedot, including the mobile application (the “ ** _App_** ”), collectively, as the “ ** _Service_** ”). As such, we have established and implemented this Privacy Policy to inform visitors to and users of the Service how we use and protect the information we collect through the Service. By accessing or using any aspect of the Service, you consent to Anedot’s collection, use, storage, deletion and disclosure of information relating to you as set forth in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is effective as of the date set forth above and is only applicable to the Site and the Service and not to any other website or mobile application that you may be able to access from the Service which may have its own data collection and use practices and policies. 

This policy answers the following questions:

  * What information do we collect about you and how do we use it?
  * Will we share your personal information with third parties?
  * What choices do you have about the collection and use of your personal information?
  * What security measures do we take to safeguard your personal information?

## What information do we collect about you and how do we use it?

### Types of Information We Collect

Personal information means information that can be used to identify and contact you. You do not need to submit personal information to access the Service generally. However, you may be required to submit personal information to access certain aspects of the Service. We may collect non-personal information such as your browser type and when, from where and how you access and use the Service. This information may be aggregated to measure the number of visits, average time spent, page views, and other statistics about users of the Service. We also may use this data to monitor and improve the Service’s performance.

We collect personal information when you create a User or an Account (each, as defined below) through the Service; subscribe to our newsletter; complete and submit registration forms, feedback forms or surveys; make or receive a contribution through the Service; or receive customer or technical support. We also collect certain personal information when we obtain verification information about you or your company through trusted third parties such as banks and credit bureaus.

To create a personal user account (each, a “ ** _User_** ”), we require you to provide certain information to create your profile, including your name, email address, passphrase, zip code and phone number. Providing additional information beyond what is required to create an account, such as your occupation, employer or a profile photo is optional, but enables you to more fully utilize the Service. 

To create an organization Account (each, an “ ** _Account_** ”) for the Service, we require you to provide certain additional information to create your profile and for verification and fraud prevention purposes, including your entity name, entity type, tax identification number, physical address, email address, phone number and bank account information, and, if Anedot determines it to be necessary, the birthdate and social security number of the principal User associated with the Account. Providing additional information beyond what is required to create an account, such as biographical information or a profile photo is optional, but enables you to more fully utilize the Service. 

When making contributions through the Service, whether or not you have created a User, you will be required to provide a payment method, such as a credit card number, and may be required to provide additional account details, a billing address, phone number, email address and zip code. You may opt to securely store your personal and payment data via DonorID, a component of the Service which facilitates easier contributions through the Service.

By submitting personal information through the Service, you authorize us to share this personal information for the purposes identified herein or as otherwise disclosed to you in the course of your use of the Service, such as responding to user inquiries, processing transactions, distributing materials, and requesting feedback.

### Third Party Privacy Policies

Through the Service, you may be able to link to technology, software and services owned and controlled by third parties (“ ** _Third Party Features_** ”). You may be permitted or required to submit personal information to access Third Party Features. Such use of Third Party Features and submission of information through Third Party Features will be subject to such applicable third party’s terms of use, terms of service and privacy policy. You agree to look solely to the applicable third party and not to Anedot to enforce your rights in relation thereto. When you have clicked on a third party logo or URL displayed on the Site or the App, or accessible through the Service, which links you to any Third Party Features, the Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use no longer applies and you must read the terms of use, terms of service and privacy policy of the third party to see how your personal information will be handled on their website.

### How We Use Your Personal Information

The personal information you provide to us will allow us to communicate with you and provide the Service to you, depending on the aspect of the Service for which you register. This includes alerting you of new products or services, features, or enhancements to the Service; verifying your identity; handling your customer service questions or issues; processing contributions; requesting feedback; distributing newsletters; and notifying you of updates or contribution opportunities we think may interest you. We may also use your email address as part of the Service in sending you messages about the Service and other general announcements. We keep track of your interactions with us, including but not limited to your activity within the Service. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, or unless we have your consent, we will not share your personal information with any person or entity other than those affiliated with us, entities acting on our behalf, and relevant third parties such as those needed to collect and maintain our servers and perform technology and related services.

We may use your personal information with non-personal information that we have collected in a manner such that the end-product does not personally identify you or any other user of the Service. We may make your personal information non-personally identifiable by either combining it with information about other users (aggregating your personal information with information about other users), or by removing characteristics (such as your name or email address) that make the information personally identifiable. This process is known as de-personalizing your information. You grant us a royalty-free, worldwide, perpetual, irrevocable and fully transferable right and license to use your personal information in connection with the creation and development of analytical and statistical analysis tools relating to the use of the customer data we collect in providing the Service (the “ ** _Analytical Data_** ”). We are expressly authorized to make any commercial use of the Analytical Data, including without limitation, sharing the Analytical Data with third parties, provided that we not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer from us any part of the Analytical Data that personally identifies any Service users.

### Do Not Track

In compliance with California legislation, AB370, effective January 1, 2014, Anedot’s practices in responding to “do not track” signals and collecting user information over time and across a network of websites when you visit the Site are as follows: We honor the request of “do not track” signals sent by your browser when you visit the Site. Additionally, Anedot does not collect user information about your online activities over time and across different websites, or authorize third parties to do so.

### Google Analytics

Anedot uses Google Analytics to help us learn about who visits the Site and what pages are being viewed.

### Cookies

“Cookies” are small bits of electronic information that a website sends to a visitor’s browser and are stored on the visitor’s hard drive. Like many websites, we employ cookies in certain areas of the Site to allow us to provide information to make your online experience more convenient. For example, when you return to the Site after logging in, cookies provide information to the Site so that the Site will remember who you are on subsequent visits, speeding up or enhancing your experience of the Service by, for instance, tailoring content to you. Cookies may also be used to keep track of shopping cart information and your login name and password. While Anedot may use cookies to track your visit to the Site, this information does not identify you personally and you remain anonymous, even if you have previously submitted personal information to Anedot through the Site or otherwise. You may still access the Service if you set your browser not to accept cookies.

Third parties whose websites are accessible through links on the Site may also use their own cookies when you link to their site or service. Anedot does not control these third parties’ use of cookies and cannot guarantee that they will uphold the same privacy standards as Anedot. Anedot expressly disclaims any and all liability related to the collection, use or disclosure of information by third parties. You should review the privacy policies of any third party sites that you visit through a link from the Site to understand how these third parties use cookies and the information they collect through cookies. Most cookies are “session cookies” which means that they are automatically deleted at the end of each session. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you a chance to decide whether or not to accept it.

### Log Information

Our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit the Site. This information includes your Internet Protocol address, your browser type and version, the search engine you used to find the Service, if any, which Service you use, and when and how long you use them. We use this information to monitor and analyze how users use the Service, to provide customer service and to maintain and improve the Service. We may also collect similar information from emails we may send to you which then help us track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients. The information allows for more accurate reporting and improvement of the Service.

### Children’s Privacy

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13, or allow them to create an account for the Service. We take children’s privacy seriously, and encourage parents to play an active role in their children’s online experience at all times.

## How We Share Your Personal Information With Other Users

### Sharing Your Information

We use your personal information to provide the Service to you, facilitate the initiation and receipt of contributions, handle your customer service questions or issues and send communications to you about promotions, updates, or special offers from Anedot that may be of interest to you. The personal information uploaded by you through the Service will be shared only with authorized persons to whom you specifically grant access. This may include sharing information about you requested by persons or organizations to which you choose to contribute (each, a “ ** _Recipient_** ”), unless you opt to donate anonymously, and among platforms with which the Service integrates to provide more features and a better experience to you. We may also use your depersonalized personal information to provide analyses of our users in the aggregate (including Analytical Data subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy) to prospective partners and other third parties. We will also share the personal information we collect from you under the following circumstances, and you expressly authorize us to share your information as follows:

  * _Protection of rights_. We will share personal information if we have a good faith belief that (i) access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process, such as a court order or subpoena, or a request by law enforcement or governmental authorities, (ii) such action is appropriate to enforce our Terms of Use for the Service, including any investigation of potential violations thereof, (iii) such action is necessary to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues associated with the Service, or (iv) such action is appropriate to protect the rights, property or safety of Anedot, its employees, users of the Service or others.
  * _Asset transfers_. If we become involved in a merger, acquisition or other transaction involving the sale of some or all of Anedot’s assets, user information, including personal information collected from you through your use of the Service, could be included in the transferred assets. Should such an event occur, we will use reasonable means to notify you through email and/or a prominent notice on the App and/or Site.
  * _Service Providers_. We may share your personal information with service providers (including our affiliates that provide services on our behalf) that we engage for the purpose of processing information on our and your behalf. Additionally, we may partner with other companies to process, analyze, and/or store data, including, but not limited to, Analytical Data. While providing services for us, these companies may access your personal information. To the extent applicable, we require these entities to comply with this Privacy Policy and appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

### Additional Information You Should Know About Third Parties

The Site may contain direct links to websites operated by our partners and other entities. These third party websites may collect information about you when you visit them or otherwise communicate with them. This Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of third party websites linked to the Site or accessible through the Service, including with respect to information received by Recipients and shared with their respective affiliates and partners. Although we encourage such third parties to adopt and follow their own privacy policies, we are not responsible for their collection and use of your personal information. You should refer to the privacy policies and statements of other websites or contact the respective webmasters of those websites to obtain information regarding their information collection, use and disclosure policies. 

## What choices do you have about the collection and use of your personal information?

### Control of Your Information

You may update or delete your personal information or modify your account preferences for the Service by accessing the account interface provided through the Service. Please note that if you disable your account, we will keep your contact information on file, and may retain other account information for a reasonable period of time afterward for the purpose of internal account management and fraud prevention activities.

### Opting Out of Receiving Communications From Us

We may occasionally email you with information about contribution opportunities or new services. If you no longer want to receive our newsletter, emails or other announcements, you may unsubscribe by writing to us at [help@anedot.com](mailto:help@anedot.com) or following the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of our emails. Please note that you cannot unsubscribe from certain correspondence from us, including messages relating directly to your account. Your contact information will also be shared with those Recipients to whom you contribute; if you wish to stop receiving further communications from a Recipient, please contact them directly.

### Mediation

You agree that, in the event any dispute or claim arises out of or relating to this Privacy Policy, you and Anedot will attempt in good faith to negotiate a written resolution of the matter directly between the parties. You agree that if the matter remains unresolved for forty-five (45) days after notification (via certified mail or personal delivery) that a dispute exists, all parties shall join in mediation services in Baton Rouge, Louisiana with a mutually agreed mediator in an attempt to resolve the dispute. Should you file any arbitration claims, or any administrative or legal actions without first having attempted to resolve the matter by mediation, then you agree that you will not be entitled to recover attorneys’ fees, even if you would otherwise be entitled to them.

## What security measures do we take to safeguard your personal information?

The personal information that you provide to us is stored on servers, which are located in secured facilities with restricted access, and protected by protocols and procedures designed to ensure the security of such information. In addition, we restrict access to personal information to Anedot employees, independent contractors and agents who need to know this information in order to develop, operate and maintain the Service. All Anedot personnel who have access to this information are trained in the maintenance and security of such information. However, no server, computer or communications network or system, or data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect user information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or through the use of any of the Service and you acknowledge and agree that you provide such information and engage in such transmissions at your own risk. Once we receive a transmission from you, we will endeavor to maintain its security on our systems. We may retain private data such as your credit card number after the transaction for which such information is provided has been processed, which will at all times be stored in a manner compliant with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard.

In the event that personal information you provide to us is compromised as a result of a breach of security, when appropriate we will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation, notify you and take the necessary steps to comply with any applicable laws and regulations.

## Notification of Changes

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time and we will post all changes on the Site and/or the App.

## Questions? Contact Us

If you have any questions about our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at [privacy@anedot.com](mailto:privacy@anedot.com "privacy@anedot.com").

## Terms of Service

Please read the [Terms of Use](https://anedot.com/terms "Terms of Use") governing the use of the Site and the Service.
